

# Ildar Ishalin Almaty, Kazakhstan

+7 (708) 978-85-15 ildar.ishalin@gmail.com tlg: @invent2on

### **ABOUT**

Android developer from Almaty, Kazakhstan. Have ~7 years of experience, worked with various projects including messengers, mapbased applications and banking. Currenly leading two teams of four and three android developers. Have organized a monthly android meetup exploring and discussing latest technologies. Have developed high quality apps for millions of users.

Looking for interesting projects with strong developers to learn from

# **SKILLS**

- Android: Kotlin, Coroutines, Java, RxJava, Dagger, Koin, Glide, Coil, Retrofit, KMM, Compose, Firebase
- Tools: Git, Jenkins, Gitlab, Sonarqube, Gradle
- Testing: Junit, Robolectric, Mockito, Expresso, Barista, TDD

# **EDUCATION**

AUPET, Almaty Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering 2008 - 2012

UCTI, Kuala Lumpur Master's degree, Mobile Computing Systems 2012 - 2014

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Jan 2022 - present - Tredo. Android Team Lead

- Leading a team of three android developers
- Code review, mentoring, consulting
- Set up development process, documentation rules and code style

Jan 2019 - present - Prime Source. Android Developer, Android Team Lead

- Managing and supporting several outsource projects built with my architecture, doing code review and providing developers with tools.
- Have developed a scalable, easy to use, production ready framework for multi-module android development (also for KMM) based on clean architecture.
- Refactored legacy projects
- Currently leading a team of four android developers. Mentoring, exploring new technologies and solutions.
- Worked with SCRUM and Kanban
- Tech stack: Kotlin, Coroutines, Koin, Clean Architecture, KMM, Compose
- Built several localization solutions for different approaches

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019 - Veon. Android Developer

- Built a scalable application for different countries but with one core.
- Worked in high speed agile production team aimed at fast delivery and high quality.
- Tech stack: Java, RxJava, Dagger, Retrofit
- Built a complex caching system with RxJava
- Covered 70% of the code with unit and ui tests

Oct 2015 - Nov 2017 - Gamma Technologies. Android Developer

- Worked with three messengers: iTys, Ruta and Cryptochat all with similar core, but with different features
- Refactoring, fixing bugs, adding new features as a junior developer
- Fully developed reply to, edit and delete message features (including backend) earlier than WhatsApp
- Developed audio message UI with separate seekbars for each message
- Developed combined rss news feed with pagination and checking for new updates